Okay.
You all right?
Yeah.
You'd think these trips would get easier,
but it's just the opposite.
Well, I feel the same way, Ange.
I know this is what we do.
This is our life.
But it just seems like the world
is moving so
...and right now
things are changing so much.
They sure are.
I'll tell you somelhing.
It's not gonna be easy for our kids.
They're going into a different world
than the one you and I came into.
Yeah.
You know,
bolh our kids are doing great.
But it worries me when Danny
doesn't take school seriously.
Him missing class.
That could come out-
It might hurt him when he's out
looking for a job, you know?
The oompelifion out there.
When I was shining out...
...you oould make caplain if you put
your head down and did your work.
Bu: young gup coming up now...
Companies want things faster
and cheaper.
And 50 guys compete for every job.
Everything3 different,
and big wheels are turning.
You 90h be slrong
to survive out there.
I hr what you're saying.
It's gonna be okay, right?
Oh, yeah.
Gonna be okay.
This is a special
security announcement.
Please maintain control
of your personal belongings stall limes.
Unattended baggage is subject
to search, inspection and removal.
- I love you.
- Love you too.
- Have a safe trip.
- I'll call you from there.
They're here!
Hurry, Muse!
What the hell are you doing?
Why aren't you out on the watel?
You know what you're supposed to do!
You should be out there
earning money!
But we caught a ship last week.
That was last week!
The boss wants money today!
Bring Garaad another ship soon...
...or you will answer for it!
Everybody, get back to work now!
ShlyoutofmywaytodﬂY-
Huh!“!
I'm going to gel: us something big!
Those who want to make money,
come.
Muse, take me with you.
Does your sister know you're here?
She's selling khat up there.
This is her best stuff.
When we get a big ship,
you will be well paid.
You want to work?
Doymhwummieexahoafi?
Go, go.
I'm ready.
- What do you have for me?
- Monevy.
- When are you gonna give it to me?
- As soon as we're paid.
Spread out!
Let my olher man choose his crew.
Next time bring me somelhing
if you want to work.
Come on, Bilal.
Hey, Skinny, I can sheer your boat.
If you choose me, you won't regret it.
Okay, Elmi.
I need somebody slrong.
Somebody like this?
I want him.
Why did he pick him?
He's from another village.
MOVE!
Faster, move faster!
See if you can get more power.
Okay.
You!
Get over here!
Come help us!
Okay, pull it in!
Sign right there, sir.
You have a good day.
- Hello, Cap. Let me get that for you.
- Morning.
Attention, all crew. All crew.
'If Ilﬂdeparluralfuaeout.
- Hevy, good to see you, Cap.
- Shane. Good to see you.
- Good to sea you.
-Hey. Carry on.
- Hey, hos?
-Yh?
Get on that safely rail, huh?
- Kenny.
- Yeah?
I want you to go down to the deck offioe,
grab Jimmy, get on the Lodeslar.
That ballast, move it five points.
- Take care of that now.
- You got it.
Hank's the family, Cap?
Oh, you know.
Andrea's a champ, one kid gone,
another kid going.
How are the boxes?
Oh, you know.
Just puﬂing a few last containers on.
Twenty-four hundred tons of
commercial cargo, 200 tons of food aid...
...1 tons of freshwater,
250 metric tons of fuel bunlceled.
Walk me through the plan.
So here we are in Salalah.
Travel down the coalition corridor
to Djibouti.
Then we emit the shipping Ina
south of Socolra.
Sondra, okay.
Then we're on our own down the coast
through the Somali Basin...
...alllhe way down to Mombasa.
“Ieneedfivenlinlates
onthatlaefarbun.
We should be able
to unload the containers around 0800.
Well, let's lighten up security.
We are going
around the Horn of Africa, right?
We got pirate cages. They were all open.
All lhe doors are unlocked.
I want evverylhing closed, locked,
even in port.
- Right.
- Fine. Ready to leave. 1500.
Absolutely, Cap. You got it.
Show the gangway.
Last lines in.
Okay. Lower it.
Sixteen-B ready. Take it up.
Tighten it up.
Hey, slow down.
Bow clear.
Stern lines are clear.
Bow thruster full starboard.
Bow thruster on.
All lines clear. Ship is under way.
- Dead slow ahead.
Keep those hatches locked down.
- Cap.
- Morning.
Check that rigging.
- Shane.
- Yeah?
We need those time sheets.
She's winking at me.
But it iums out that's what they do.
I'll show you this plea. I'll lake you.
I'll have two beers
and a buckelful of sin, please.
Yeah. About done with that coffee?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, we're done.
That's 15. CUF-
Back to work. Come on, let's go.
Jesus.
- See you down there, Mike.
Their main route is packed
with ships...
...but we can't aﬂack a herd.
This one is alone.
Morning.
Hay'! cap'
.68?-
'Morning, Cap-
Shane, I want to do some security drills,
unannounced.
Starling now.
What? Fire, man overboard?
Everylhing.
Ken, you're the duly offioel?
- Yeah, Cap.
- Right.
Boat with two armed men is approaching
on your slarboard beam.
- No, no. Whisﬂe first.
- Let's go.
That way the pirates know we're aware
of them and are ready to defend the ship.
Hustle up. Let's go.
Mariana“ new.
All crew.
All men to yourstafions on deck.
Repeat,
all men to your deck slafions now.
Let's do this.
Come on- Get those ken off your hip.
Put them in your pocket. Come on, gum.
Pirates capture you
and find those
...they'll have to every door
on this ship.
Get those hoses on.
Bring it around, bring around,
bring around.
- Walnh it, man.
- Ready with number six.
All right.
You tied up?
All done here, Shane.
- Hevy, Cap, this is Shane. Do you read?
- Yeah, Shane, go ahead.
Things are looking good down here.
We're geﬂing close with the hoses.
All right. Let me know
when you're ready down there.
'Bovine:
Shane, come up to the bridge.
Okay-.
What's up, Cap? Everylhing okay?
I don't like the look of that.
- Yeah, Cap.
- Chief, I want all your gum on slaiion.
Still in the drill?
This is real-vlorld. Someone coming up
on our slarboard quarter.
Gd! it.
Port, 5 degrees.
Let's see if they follow us.
Port, 5.
Get the crew back
to their muster slafions.
Right.
Aﬂzenfion, all crew.
Retum to your muster slafions.
Repeetlehnnbyourmuslarstafions.
This is not a drill.
This is a real-vlorld situation.
- Yeah, Cap.
- I want to come up to 122.
Second mate and helmsman
to the bridge.
You're good. Bring her on up.
New get me U.S. Marifime Emergency.
Two skiﬂs.
Can't tell how many they're carrying.
Copy that.
There's no answer
at the U.S. Marifime Emergency line.
- Raise the UKMTO.
- Right.
What's up?
We got two skiﬂs approaching.
Got on the radar.
YeahJhisisfinMeerskAleberm.
Hsrisfinuphin.
UKMTO.
Opqmm.
Tfisistheldaelsklklabenn.
Ourposifionishleqleeshlorh
bvfideqaaeuseesr.
Ouroouneisﬂifi.
Ourspeedisﬂluuots.
We have two skiﬂs approaching
at a dislanoe of 1.5 miles...
a possible molhership following.
'Cqikﬂubune.
Alert your crew,
get your fire hoses ready...
...and follow lockdown procedures.
Yeah. Is that it?
I'm relaying your transmission now,
but chances are it's just fishermen.
They're not here to fish.
She's really big! Get ready!
You worry about yourself, skinny rat!
Bolh skiﬂs carrying armed men.
- Dislanoe?
- One and a quarter miles and closing.
- Yeah, Cap.
- I wanna bring it up to 125.
- You're slill good.
- One twenty-five.
Brolhers,
we're going to make a lot of money!
Slow down! The waves are too big!
They're at one mile new, Cap.
Only one mile.
Coalilion Warship 237,
this is Maarsk Alabama.
Coafifiunwaiﬂﬂp 231,
Maaisk Alabama.
Go, Alabama.
Our pesilion is 2 degrees 2 north
by 49 degrees 19 east.
Ourcourse is 180.
Ourspeed is 18.5 knots.
Mb are being approached
by two pirate skilfs..
a possible rmﬂuelship following.
We require immediate assistance.
We have a crew of20.
We ere preparing our weapons now
but request air support if possible.
cow?
Copy, Alabama.
Be aware, a gunship is in the air.
ETA your posilion, five minutes.
Five minutes. Thank you, 237.
Did you hear that? Did you hear that?
We've got to get out of here!
Turn back, turn back!
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
Come on! Keep going!
Yeah, we get one down.
But the olher one's slill coming.
Half a mile out.
We need to make a bigger wake.
- Yeah.
- Canoel the limils. One two nine.
Yeah, you're on the edge
with Cylinder Number 5.
Do“.
- Port, 5 degrees.
Faster, faster!
They're at a quarter mile new.
Starboard, 5 degrees.
Hurry, hurry! Go!
We're pushing this engine too hard!
Faster, faster!
Come on, let's go!
This thing is busted.
- Then fix it!
- I'm ﬂying!
They're not messing around.
Lit us up from miles away.
Musfve been tacking us.
Why doesn't the company
give us armed guards?
Move it in. The caplain's here.
Blips on the radar that are clocking
at 27 knals.
They were moving.
We cannot oulrun these gum.
Obviously, we all just went
lhrough a dangerous silualion.
Two skiﬂs, bolh with armed intruders.
Now, we all know that's a hrd
in these waters, but you performed well.
The ship performed well.
The aulhorifies
have been made aware...
...so I think we have the situafion
well in hand.
From now on,
we just follow our normal dulies.
Mate, what do you got?
Yeah. We're all on double shifls
unfil we make it through these waters.
All right. Chief, n you keep
your engineers on roster'?
We'll keep a guy in the ECR
around the clock.
All right. Enjoy your coffee.
Cap.
They're coming back.
Amen. Yeah, that's right.
If Ihey come back, we'll follow procedure.
They worked today, lheyll work again.
We got the speed, we got the height,
we got hoses that can sink those skiﬂs.
We will follow the procedures even if
we have to shut down, lock down...
...go dead in the water
and wait for help.
Now, wait. I'm a u-
Okay, I'm a union guy, okay?
Twenty-five years. ll right?
I'm telling you now that they're
not paying me enough to fight pirates.
You all signed up for a route
around the Horn of Africa.
- What did you expect?
- I didn't sign up for the Navy over here.
- You signed up for the mule.
- For a cargo ship.
Mmdklyweaqzuﬂ.
Why don't we get out of here?
Put room between us.
- Go where?
- In eight hours...
-...we could be a hundred miles from here.
- Hundred to a 150.
There's five pirate bands
in this part of the world.
You go out 300 miles, you run into one,
go 6, you run into anolher.
Our job is to move the cargo
as fast as possible. That's the job.
If anybody doesn't like it,
if anybody wants off...
...if anybody doesn't like this roule
between Salalah, Djibouli and Mombasa...
"some to my allies
nd sign the paperwork per the union...
...and you'll be on the first ﬂight home
out of Mombasa.
Enjoy your coffee.
Let's get back to work.
Go get those gum squared away,
will you?
The ocean was rough. Really rough.
Hufan, I'm telling you,
our boat couldn't take it.
Nolhing was working for us.
Hurry UP-
We need a bigger one for that ship.
I want this welded by the morning...
...by tomorrow, got it?
Elmi.
When will that engine be ready?
We've 90h fix it.
This thing is old and weak.
It's a piece of shit.
Shut up and fix it
for your crew of women.
Why don't you give me your engine?
Shut up, Skinny. You talk too much.
I may be skinny, but I'm not a coward.
What did you say?
Sly it again!
You think you're somebody?
The coward is the first one in the grave.
Captain, Ibis is Shane.
Yeah, go ahead.
Hhinkyoubdterqetuphﬂfi-
Coming.
- Where are they?
- Port quarter.
One-point-savan mil, plain.
Guy's coming on his own.
Sound the alarm.
Get U.S. Marifime Emergency for me.
Muster slafions. This is not a drill.
Everyone to muster slafions.
- This is note drill.
- Come on.
Shit.
Come on. Let's go. Go.
- Yeah, Cap.
- They're coming back.
I want max ma. Take the limils off.
Copy that. Canceling ll limils.
- Five degrees slarboard.
Starboard, 5 degrees.
Get read!!-
U.S. Marifime Emergency line.
This is the Maarsk Alabama.
We are under pirate aﬂack at a...
- What's happening?
- Ken, get out here.
- I need eyes on the wing. Skiff coming in.
- I'm on it.
Our course is 166.
Our speed is 19 knots.
Copy that, Alabama.
Relaying to mililary channels now.
Copy that.
They're coming in fast, Cap.
Alabama.
Alabama ship.
Somali coast guard.
This is a rouline check.
5110p your ship now.
We ere coming aboard.
We're here to help you.
- Shane, they're dead ashem.
- Jesus Christ.
- Yeeh, Cap.
- We're gonna need the hoses.
Yeah, your pumps arB 900d-
- Count it down for me, Shane.
- Yeah. They're at 800 yards.
- Prepare for hard turns.
- Stop nowl
Standing by.
- Alabama, this is your final warning.
Stop the ship.
They're not shopping.
Show them who we are, Muse.
Shoot at them!
Shots fired! Shots fired! Hit the hoses.
Turn!
Coming in close, Cap.
Shane! Hose seven has slipped.
Bay 17. I'm on it. Shit.
- Be careful.
- I'm on Channel 3.
It's clear over there!
They're coming back in.
Untie the ladder.
Give me the other one.
Shoot him!
Let's go, let's go!
Hurry up, Bilal.
Move your ass, kid.
Channel 3. Shane, get out of there.
Geteverybody
dwmbfiaeerugimloom.
I need you in command there.
Stop him!
All crew! All crew!
All crew to the engine room!
All crew to the engine room now!
Come on, let's go. Move it.
Come on, men.
Higher. Get it higher.
- Perl:, 30 degrees.
-Perl:, 30 degrees.
Hook it on!
They got the ladder up.
Starboard, 3O degrees.
GGIOUIOHIIYWQY-
- Perl:, 30 degrees.
-Perl:, 30 degrees.
Starboard, 3O degrees.
Starboard, 30.
Summdsﬂnzfimatm.
Hang on.
Just get together against the wall.
- Cronan. Cronan.
- Yeah.
Hold them by the door.
We'll get a head oount.
Go down to the door.
- Mike?
- Yeah.
- How long lill you can shut her down?
- Five minutes.
Four pirates on board.
Four pirates,
coming towards us down the main deck.
- Lock down the bridge.
- Yeah.
Lislen up. We have been boarded
by four armed pirates.
You know the drill.
Westayhidderumnleilervlhet
Izbrﬂwamarlytnoslaqes.
We slay locked down unfil help arrives.
Nounewnuesununfihjwhear
finmmumsspassmldfsuppelfinn.'
Jesus.
LHhe pirates find you, remember,
you know the ship.
They don't.
Make them feel like they're in charge...
...but keep them away from the generator
and the engine controls.
Stick bgelher...
...and we'll be all right.
Good luck.
Take everybody to the beltom
of the engine room.
Hide them behind the cylinders.
Try to split them
into groups of threes and fours.
- Hevyl Don't move! Don't move!
- Okay, okay.
- Don't move, I said! Don't move!
- All fight. All fight.
Okay.
Okay. All right. Okay.
Don't move! We have four!
- All fight, all fight.
- Don't move! We have four! Four!
No, no.
Get away. Get over there.
“Win.
Relax. Nobody get hurt.
No I Qaed here.
Just business. We want money.
When we get paid,
everylhing gonna be okay.
The ship.
Where from?
The ship? America.
It's an American ship.
America? Yes! Yes!
You?
Yankee?
Me? Yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Yankee-Irish. Yeah.
From now on
this one is called Irish, okay?
Irish. Irish.
Okay, Irish. What else you carrying?
What do you mean?
'L'V?Cal?
TV and car-? No, no.
We just got the food-
Dollars?
We do. Kenny?
Kenny, what do we have in the safe?
We got like, what, $30,000 in the safe?
Yeah, we get like- We have-
In the safe, we get $30,000.
It's yours.
Thirty thousand dollars?
What am I? Do I look like a beggal?
What's that?
It's all right.
Hey, calm down! Calm down.
Get back there.
Yeah, yeah, over here.
We got a problem.
We pushed the ship too hard.
We're off the grid.
That means
the computer's now off-line.
- Caplain. Caplain.
- The ship's broken.
No one get hurt
if you don't play no game.
Ifs- The ship's broken. We had to go-
Nobody gels hurt. Easy.
Hey!
- Look at me.
- Sure.
I'm the plain now.
Watch this ugly one.
What are you doing?
I'm going to fix it.
Do you know how?
Hold the gun on him.
I've got him, don't worry.
Don't mess with anylhing
you don't know.
Come on, man.
- What are you doing?
- Just take care of that guy.
Stop the games.
Where is the crew?
I don't know. I don't know.
I'm hero with you.
- Where is your crew?
- I don't know. Here, I'll call lhem up.
I'll gal: them up here, ll right?
This is the plain speaking.
The pirales demand all crew members
to lhe bridge. All-
Every crew...
minute, I will kill someone.
One minute.
Another minute, I kill somebody.
Ikilldlyourfiiermtlmnlinute.
I will no call again.
Get that one
and put him against the wall.
- I'm ﬂying-
- You think we playing?
- No, I'm doing the best-
- No play. No play.
- I'm doing the best I can.
- Easy, I kill you. Easy.
No, no. Look. You don't have to do that.
- Come on.
- You play? You play?
Take it easy, take it easy. No, no, no.
- No, look, look.
- Stop play!
Don't shoot him. Don't shoot him.
You're gonna shoot somebody, shoot me.
- Where is the crew, Irish?
- Folty seconds!
I don't know. I'm here with you.
No. Where is the crew?
I see nobody.
- I'm the plain. I'm the plain.
-Thirly second!
If you're gonna shoot somebody,
you shoot me.
- You killing him.
-It's my ship.
- Listen to me.
- You killing him.
I'm the plain.
I'm the plain, not them.
- Twenty second!
- This is between us.
I'm ﬂying to slraighten this out. Are you?
This is how you solve your problems?
You said you just wanted money.
You said this was just business.
Is this business?
- Is this how you do business?
- Ten seconds.
Die right now.
Wait.
I want to search the ship.
You wanna search the ship?
I want to search every lock and hold
of the ship now.
- You wanna search the ship?
- Now.
All right. We'll search the ship.
We'll shirt on the nav deck
and work our way down.
Webelbrhope
"Bemifiﬂmyptwnrstayson.
Wewonibeableloseeifitgoesoli
I'll take you. We'll search the ship.
But you shop threatening my men.
- No game.
Let's go.
All right? All right. awd-
Take his radio.
All right. Okay.
Go.
Geﬂa get these lights off.
They're gonna see us.
We need to shut down the generator
on the main deck.
- You think you can get up there?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna go lo lhe mess, get water.
Get everyone on lhe lower level.
All right. I'm on 2.
Just shirt at the very top.
This is E deck.
And we'll just work our way down
one by one, huh?
Cargo hold is probably where they are.
There's a lot of places to hide.
And I'm not ﬂying to trick you.
I wanna find these gum
just as much as you do.
Take his ﬂashlight.
We should just move on,
because we're wasting time here.
Like I say,
the cargo decks the best place to look.
Somebody messing with ship.
Engine room.
If we're going about this swtemafically,
we shined at the top...
...we're working our way down,
so we should 11y the cargo deck.
Problem from engine room.
We go there now.
All right. Engine room.
It's gonna be really hut down there.
Wilhout the power on,
there's no venfilafion, no air.
Maybe we should get some water
from the mess down on A deck?
- Then engine room. Go.
- Okay.
This is A deck.
So here we are.
This is the galley.
This is where we make the food.
All right. Here, some water.
Check this room.
Oh, you wanna see in here?
This is cold storage.
It's a vegetable room.
Careful in here in the bare feet.
You could cut them
on almost anylhing.
Want some of this melon?
It's left over from breakfast.
It's just gonna go bad.
It's just gonna spoil.
It's usually left out
for the first meal of the day.
Maybe we should-
Go ahead, help yourself. Here you go.
Help yourself.
It's usually for breakfast, but...
Enough. Engine room.
All right.
- Cronan. Cronan. Do you read?
- Yeah, I got you.
They're on their way to you.
One is barefoot.
Is there glass you can break,
leave on the ﬂoor by the dool?
I'll do it. Come on, let's go. Come on.
Here's the engine room.
On, my God.
Look out. There's broken glass.
Be careful.
- Put your hand up. Up your hands. Up.
- Okay, all fight.
Up.
- There's a first-aid kit-
- Put your hands up!
- Who did this?
- Nobody. It was just a dumb accident.
We should get that looked at.
There's a kit in the oonhol room.
Quiet, Irish. You think I m stupid?
I know what's going on.
We're going to search this whole room.
All of it. Now go.
Go.
I heard somelhingl
Check the other side.
There's no one here.
Please, let's go back.
Go. Right down to the boltom. Now.
They're coming. Get ready.
Keep suing. Move.
Wait. Stop here.
What? Whafd you do?
- We just-
- Look at me, Irish. Look at me.
What's wrong with your ship?
- I don't know.
- Was that you?
- I don't know what went wrong.
- No.
You'll never find this crew,
not without any power on the ship.
You'll never find them.
We'll never find them.
Irish...
...I will find.
Nutwilh him.
Look. He's gonna bleed to deaih.
Look, man, get us out of here.
You got a man injured.
Let's take care of his
"Jake the money out of the safe
and call it a day. All right?
You're bad luck, Irish.
Hey, take him upslairs.
I can't move.
Take him upslairs
and tell Najee to come.
- You go with him.
- We're gonna go?
Go!
L-lay-
Wait.
You're not gonna find anybody.
Don't talk. Go.
Your friend make fool of us?
Make us run around?
If one of them moves,
send them to their graves.
Here.
L-lay-
We got a problem.
Your buddy's hurt real bad.
We better gel: this dressed.
We got a sick bay here on board,
and this guy lawws what to do.
What happened to you?
They put glass down for me.
They got me.
Where is Muse?
In the engine room.
He wants Najee to come down.
BTiQOB-Blidqqoonuein.
Alabama bridge, come in.
Do you read?
'ﬂisisﬂaeuewoflhemelskkhbann.
Wahaveyourcaptain.
Putyourhuldoverhisnnulh.
Hay.
-No.
“lehaveyourleeder.
We have your caplain and his weapon.
We wanna bade.
Caplain for caplain. We want a deal.
Take that off of his head.
Cronan, take that off his head now.
I no kill.
Talk. Talk to your friends
so they know it's you.
Talk to your friends.
Come on, asshole. Say somelhing.
I love America.
Hey! Get me out of here!
Lidsnbvlhetheaequystaavebsay.
What happened?
'They cut my hand bad.
We'll slraighlen everylhing out laler.
Just get me out of here.
Give Irish the radio.
I'll give itto him now.
Talk.
Caplain, you know,
if you wanna get off this ship...
myoudonihaveesldlfenyrmla,
butyoucouldqetinbolulifeboet.
You could take off
off our stern...
...and you can go with the $30,000,
and you could get off this ship right now.
Dowehaveadeel?
Say we have a deal.
Okay, Irish. Deal.
- Deal, Irish, deal.
- Okay, then.
- Lisl:an, we could-
-Hey.
Thirty thousand is nolhing.
I want millions!
There. All right, there's the lifeboat.
Hey, Bilal, check it out.
If anyone moves, kill them.
Kill them!
Where is our plain?
Where is our guy?
Hey, Cap. Cap, it's Shane.
I'm not armed. I'm not armed.
No weapons. No. Hey, easy.
There's no weapons.
There's no weapons. No weapons.
Hey, Shane. Do you have the caplain?
Where is he?
- In the engine room.
- Bring him up so they can see him.
- I wanna see.
- You will.
- Bring him up so they can see him.
- He's on his way.
- Where?
- Here he is. Yeah, there he is.
- Where?I
- See? See? There he is. There.
What's going on, Skinny?
Do what they say
and get me out of here.
Be slrong, man.
Now let's do this. We'll bring up your guy.
You gel: in, you buckle up.
We drop you in, and then
you're on your way. Okay? Okay?
No. You come with us.
Till we get our guy back.
- No, no, no. You'll get your guy back.
- No way!
- Hevyl Hey!
- Get in!
Listen! Hey!
You come, or I kill everybody!
I don't care!
It's your choice!
- All fight! All fight!
- You go! You go! You're going!
Chief, bring the guy up now.
It's gonna be okay. Bring him up.
- Shane, you got the crew.
- Don't go, Cap. Don't get in there.
- We 90h get them off the ship.
- Nat like this.
Cap, you can't do this.
Goddamn it, Cap!
All right, who's driving this thing?
“Filth him.
Bilal, hold the gun on him.
Now, look, it's very simple to operate.
On, off, shirt, shop.
Compass to follow your heading.
You see your throlﬂe there.
- You got a squawlt box.
- Gas, gas. Enough gas?
Plenty of fuel to get you to Somalia.
438p. we w! #199"?-
- All right. Send him on in. I'm coming out.
Okay, send him in. Let him go.
Let him go!
Go. Send the plain out.
All right, now, that handle, see?
You're gonna move that up and down.
You 90h pump it, one, two,
three, four, five, and then you drop.
Cepmomeonout.
Cap? Cap. what's going on in there?
Just however many times it takes...
...pump it, then you're in the water,
and off you go.
Go!
Go back!
Hay. cap!
Goddamn it! No!
- Capl
- Nol
Sit! Sit!
Here!
Go.
Irish, it's only us now.
Stand clear.
- Make a hole.
Mikﬂ WW-
Copy.
- Caplain's in Combat.
CTF 151 ,
this is Beinbridge Charlie-Oscar. Over.
Captain, {his is Admiral Howard.
A U. S-ﬂagged cargo ship,
the Maersk Alabama...
been hijacked 820 nautical miles
west of your current
Fourmaruhavehlenheshipkoaptain
hostaqeinalifeboet.
Presumed Somali pirates. Over.
Roger, ma'am.
Do we have any olher informafion? Over.
Noteﬂhisfinmbutbestguess
hhwemadngmrupsamnmm.
Yourolderselebplooeed
mdinlaluept.
FulfilarbfollwLTlmisisCTF 151 out.
Ops, prep ScanEagle.
Need aerial surveillance.
Aye, sir.
COS, this is the plain.
Come to full power.
- TAO, gal: posilion.
-TAO, aye.
Bridge, caplain, full left rudder.
Come to course 285.
Hufan, do you read me?
Hufan, can you hear me?
Where's your boss?
He should be with us by now.
Don't worry. He's coming.
Stupid hand.
Slop whining.
You sound like a lilﬂe girl.
You wanted to come with us.
You asked for this.
I didn't think this would happen.
I could lose my foot.
You have to be ready for anylhing.
This game isn't for the weak.
You okay, Irish?
Yeah.
Your face looks scared.
But evverylhing gonna be okay.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
In two dam we'll be ealing in Somalia.
Rice. Goat meat.
You'll like.
My boss talk to ship company.
Insurance man come, bag of dollars...
comm.
What is it?
It's a gift.
L-lay-
Irish.
You lie, Irish. Your ship no broke.
They come Somalia too.
More money.
Looks like they're hding north
to tho closest point of Ind.
And that's only gonna take them
36 hours at the most?
Just 90h slay with them
fill the Navy gels here.
Give me some khat.
Why?
You've had more than your share.
Saw who? Give me some more!
Shut up!
Both of you, shut up.
Just hke it.
This is it?
That's all I have.
- Where is the rest?
- I don't have any.
It's all gone.
You are useless.
I should have taken it from you.
Irish, it's taxes.
This money, taking you, that's all it is.
You come to our waters, you got to pay.
We were in international waters.
Not your waters, intemafional waters.
We were carrying food
for slarving people in Africa.
Even Somalis.
Yeah, sun.
Rim counties “ks in he“: Sound's.
Big ships come to our water...
"Jake all the fish out.
- What's left for us to fish?
- So you're fishermen?
Yeah, we're all fishermen.
Hey, let me clean out that cut.
Let me get the first-aid kit, clean that out.
It's gonna get infected.
No.
How about the kid?
Can I look at his foot?
No.
They'll fix him when we get back.
Come on, he's barefoot.
You three get sandals.
He's got bare feet.
Go ahead, go.
All right.
Just gonna get the kit.
Go ahead, come here. It's all right.
Your foot. Give me your foot.
Come on.
Let me see it. It's all right.
How old are you, anyway?
What are you, 16, 17?
You're too young to be out here
doing this.
No talking.
Hey! Hey!
He's got a knife!
Hey! What you gonna do with this?
Go back. Get back there.
UAV ScanEagle shows
the lifeboat is currenﬂy...
...126 nautical miles
off the Somali
...moving on course 305 atfive knots...
the molhership dd in the wallar
at mil to the northeast.
We have any idea
who these gum are?
Themdhersfaipisehiwamaefidairlg.
AooollingbONIJfaetvesaefsurlder
finoomolofSomeiwuludGuaad.
“Iehworkirlgonqelfirlgﬂaalbs
oﬂhekizheppels.
If this is Gd': guys, they're looking
for payday, which mns they'll ialk.
If we can get them talking,
we can wear them down. Over.
Frank, this thing is running big here,
and there's a lot of pressure building.
TTIeVWIileHousehopes
lhiscanberesolvedpeaoefully"
...but whatever happens,
Captain Phillips does not reach Somalia.
I undersland, admiral,
but we're gonna need some time.
I think if we press too hard,
we put the hoslage at risk.
We're gonna need to use
some helical pafienoe. Over.
Do yourbest to talk them down, Frank,
but you're on the clock.
We're deploying a SEAL teem with USS
Boxer and USS Halyburlpn as support
If you haven't gotten Phillips beck
by the time they arriva...
SEAL: will take cars of if.
I undersland all, admiral.
Can I have some water, please?
Wate r?
Drive this thing right!
Calm down. We're on the ocean.
I should throw you off this boat
right now!
You need to sit down and relax.
Hey, water.
Hay. Hey.
That's enough.
Take it away.
From now on this water is only for us.
Stop being such an asshole.
You've gal: to control him.
Just drive and shut up.
Hufan, can you hear me?
Are you having trouble?
No trouble, Irish. Slow piece of shit.
Yeah, yeah. Shallow-draft.
And you're fighting the current.
Gull: inks that irrllo amount.
I know what I'm doing.
Yeah, yeah, sure, you do. Of course.
You're the caplain now.
Oh, hey, plain...
don't we open up that hainh
and get a lilﬂe more air in here?
What's wrong with you?
Don't talk to me.
A lilﬂe air might do him some good.
Yeah, open the hainh so your crew...
No tricks. No. No tricks, Irish.
Hufan, can you hear me?
We should be heading nonhwest.
We've gel: to gel: to Gd': port.
I am, but there's a lot of wind.
- Just go!
- Okay, then let me do it.
Muse? Ara you there?
Aleyoulhele?
Hufan, where are you?
I'm having trouble with the engine.
l-leedhzama.
mbehalaasaoonaslcan.
Hey, we're alone out here.
We need you to pick us up.
We've got to get out of this lifeboat.
Shutupuldlislarubnle.
You screwed up gelling the ship...
...ao Gained y:...
...ordon'tooma beck at all.
Sounds like there's problem.
ls there problem?
Problem.
No problem, Irish.
Everylhing gonna be okay.
- Yes, sir.
- Hera's the Ietastfrom SOCOM.
Bdmbfidqefitﬂaesurufilyourenival
bnegdieteesunerxbr.
But upon boarding,
you will assume command.
'The Illlhital-Iousehasaulflofizad
anynlaansnecessalylorasolvalfris.
Roger that.
Boss, we're selling up comma
in the bird right now.
I need air.
When are we going to be home?
I can't feel my foot anymore.
It's like hell in here.
You wanna tell him
maybe not to do that?
He wants air.
Well, that thing is slill lded.
He's gal: the clip in il:.
Talk too much. Too much.
Gonna need some more water.
When we get home...
...you'll get a million bolﬂes of it.
- All the water you want.
- Really?
Last year I took a Greek ship.
Six million dollars.
Six million dollars?
So, what are you doing here?
Shut up, Irish.
Too much talk.
Your problem isn't me lallcing lo you.
Your problem is you not listening.
You think you have any power here?
- Let him go.
- I should shoot you and be done.
Take your gun off him.
I'm the caplain.
Who do you think you are?
You're taking his side?
You let the American
do whatever he wants!
I'm losing oonholl
It's the Americans.
Gal: something to fie the doors.
Alabama lifeboat, this is Frank Cashellano,
commander of the USS Bainbridga.
We wanna get Caplain Phillips back
safely and end lhis lhing peacefully.
- No move!
- All fight.
Alabama lifeboat, come in.
Nomifihly anion.
Nonfifihlyantionﬂodfiaeda.
We are just fishermen.
Calm down, brother.
Wdlaheleforlfnecaphinmzatforyou.
They have a spy with them.
HW. you. Who are you?
My name is Nemo.
I work with the U.S. Navy.
“Iejustwuutbtdk.
I talk English.
I want 1O million dollars.
It's not that
...but we'll work on it.
Inlhemeenfinle,
whetiflblimyouaonlefoodundwater?
No tricks, or your plain dd.
Requesﬂnhavepildladderluvmed
andaonaeoraeslamirugby.
Sham Murphy?
Huh, fink me.
Lieutenant Hicks. You're entering
a mililary engagement zone, sir.
Need you to bring the ship left to 210.
We are here to escort you to Mombasa.
Your caplain'll be in good hands.
All right. You heard him, gum.
OSS, keep the camera on the lifeboat.
ASTAC, eye.
Sir, the boat deck is manned
and ready.
VBSS is on slaiion.
Request permission to lower the RHIBs.
Imam.
Aye, sir.
Bridge TAO, launch the RHIBs.
They're coming.
Bill, watch him.
Walnh him closely.
Irish, your crew...
"Jun.
- Ship go.
-It's the Navy clearing the area.
You belter think
about what you're doing.
Navy good. They protect us.
Back to Somalia.
The Navy's not here to protect you.
They're not here to negolialla either.
No choice.
L 90'! you.
Open your door!
We are here with your supplies.
Guns down! America, guns down!
Calm down, brolher.
We're just here to help you.
Put your guns down now!
One outside and one in the hatch.
Push the hack on the link.
Listen, we need to see our guy.
We've got supplies,
food, water for you...
nacho see out napkin.
Okay. Wait.
- Thevy want to see him.
- Bring him out.
All fight. All fight. All fight.
Okay, okay. All fight. I'm coming.
Down.
- Visual confirmation.
- You all right, caplain?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm okay. Yeah, yeah.
Listen.
Does my family know where I am?
Yes, sir. We're keeping them updated.
It's imporlant they know where I am.
I'm in Seat 15.
You understand?
All slafions, TAO, log it: Seat 15.
Break, CICWO. TAO.
Send that in CTF 151 and SOCOM.
Don't worry, sir. We'll handle it.
Get him back inside.
Shut up and don't move.
Calm down, we just want to talk.
We've got your supplies here.
Food, water.
Where's the money?
I don't wantyourfood.
lwantyournlonejr.
- We got anolheron top.
- OSS, maintain camera foolage.
- Hold on a second.
- No tricks, sahib.
Ten million dollars, sahib.
Ten million dollars.
Listen, you're hurt.
We've got doctors on board.
- Let us take care of you.
- Hurry up!
They're healing us like children.
Ten million dollars, when?
It's not that
...so we need time.
WeVBgoflolalkabouHffi-s.
Hurry up, I said!
No camera! No camera!
Gunfire, take cover!
Who fired? TAO, who fired?
- Get the RHIBs out of there.
Scrum the RHIBs, scram the RHIBs.
Are you crazy? What are you doing?
- You'll gal: us ll killed!
-Do you have to ialk ll day?
You're crazy.
What do you think you're doing?
All you do is talk!
Alabama lifeboat, come in.
MOVE.
You have to be slrong
to get what you want.
Wehavebtalk.
Just an accident. Just an accident.
Is anyone hurt?
No, American fine. American okay.
I need to hear itfrom him.
- I say he okay.
- I need to hear it from him.
Get up! Get up!
MOVE. MOVE.
- Talk.
- Yeah, yeah, it's me.
Areyou okay?
It's falling apart in here.
He just fired off a round nextto my head.
- Is the leader there?
- Yeah, he can hear you.
Captain, listen to me.
We will not talents this.
As captain, you're responsible
for the lives of everyone onboerd.
Right now
you are pulling them in jeopardy.
We wanna resolve this thing
peacefully.
Isfsfirldeviayomofhisbgelfaer
befoleaonleoraegeishaut.
Alabama lifeboat, respond.
I talk when I go Somalia.
Sit down.
Sit down!
- TAO, lifabcat is under way.
-TAO, aye.
Caplain, sir, the lifeboafs 12 hours
from the Somali coast.
BoxarandHdybwbnMvealfivd.
ETA on the SEAL team is 0400.
Irish, no worry.
Everylhing gonna be okay.
Aﬂaer this, I go America.
I alwaw wanted to go America.
Go to New York, buy a can...
Hey, this situation h gallon bad.
There re 'HID more ships,
one en either side.
That one is huge.
Oh, God.
Sit down! Sit down!
- Sit down!
- Dawnl Down!
Bilal, get the ropes.
Hey, caplain, it's all over.
It's all over, caplain.
The other ropes.
There's a reason your boss took off
and isn't coming back.
He didn't wanna take on the Navy.
He's gone. He's left you alone.
You had a plan to take my ship. That didn't
work, so you thought you oould take me?
- Shut up.
- Make a run to Somalia?
They got the Navy out there.
You 90h give up. You 90h shop.
I can't shop, Irish.
The Navy is not gonna let you win.
They can't let you win.
They would rather sink this boat
than let you get me back to Somalia.
It's over.
I come too far, Irish.
I can't give up. No.
Hello?
ThasEALselairlbourld,.
Roger that.
I need to piss.
Fast.
Saltwater would be good for your foot.
He got out!
Turn the boat around!
Bill, you idiot!
Turn it! Faster, faster!
Mmre, or we'll leave you!
Caplain's in Combat.
Cap. We got two in the water.
Two in the water.
Starboard side, I see them bolh.
Two gum in the water.
- Is one of them Phillips?
- We don't know. We can't tell.
They're in the water. In the water.
One may be Phillips
and probably one pirate. We don't know.
We've gall: be sure.
Let's get a ﬂare in the air.
Find him. Don't kill him.
Don't shoot!
I'll shoot you!
Stop! What are you doing?
He's gelling all!!!
- Don't kill himl
- Belller to kill him lhan let him escape!
There he is!
I'm ordering you. Don't kill him.
Bainbridge, this is RHIB 3.
Mb have SEAL: inbound.
Fire's up, plain.
Target angle 020
on the lifeboat right new.
- Can't tell who's in the water.
- No clear shot at the Tangos.
Nobody shoals
unless there's a clear shot.
Where is he?
Here he is! Here he is!
He's here!
One more in the water.
We've got one more in the water.
Help!
All right!
- Comel
- All right!
- Comel Forward!
Gd! him.
Come!
Okay, okay.
Go in, Irish! Go! Go, Irish!
Sir, the SEAL: are coming aboard.
PlepelebboeldlfaesEALs.
Where re you go? Tell me! Tell me!
Areyou crazy?
- Where's the caplain?
- Wailing for you on the bridge, sir.
Not today!
Stop him!
That's enough!
Don't kill him!
If you kill him, we'll ll dial
- What do you want me to do with him?
- What is he doing?
Beinbridge to lifeboat,
you must surrender.
Youwillrldbepelnliltedbqoﬂnhar.
It's a helicopter!
Get to the other side!
Alabama lifeboat, respond.
Hurry! Go!
I'm Win9-
Go!
You have e choice to make, captain.
Sunendernow and this ends peacefully.
Beyond that, I cannot help you.
You must surrender.
They think you re playing gm.
Do somelhingl
You cannot win this.
Make the right decision here.
You are running out of time.
Do you undersland me?
Do you want to go
to an American prison?
Thisisyourlastchuloe.
Is that what you want?
I know how to handle America.
Give me the pistol.
They think I'm playing gm, huh?
Go!
Up ladder.
Make a hole.
Target in the hatch.
This is Bainbridge out.
They're holding a gun to Phillips' head.
He's kind of yelling
and waving his pislol back and follh.
I kill him! I kill him! Now! I kill him!
We gal: shells fired, plain.
- How many shots?
- Who fired? Who fired?
We're losing this.
Now what?
They have no respect for us.
We have to play games?
Give me the radio.
The helicopter is coming back.
America, I kill hoslage now!
I kill hoslage now!
I'm gonna put him in a body bag!
Talk. Talk.
They got a gun to my throat, and they're
gonna use a survival suit as a body bag.
You're not just a fisherman.
Men of the Alabama lifeboat,
I'm here to talk aboutyourmoney.
Repeat.
I'm here to discuss your money.
Who is this?
Hnfipnggtfiﬂbt. I
rmauumrueumvnwfiﬂmw-.
Insurance man?
Now, you are Abduwali Muse, right?
From Jariban, Punﬂand?
FromlheclensoflheHawiys
andlheDaarood?
Your friends are Adan Bilai.--
...Walid Elmi and Nour Najee.
But you are Muse. You're in command.
Is that correct?
They know us.
We spoke with the elders of your tribe.
They are coming here to negoliate a deal,
an exchange.
“Leqetourmugyouqetyoumnrley.
Bmhishesbbedominoorlfiziarlce.
Wedoniwamenyombaee
ﬂaeemhmgaNeiﬂuerzbﬂneelzbls.
It's a lie.
You're low on fuel.
We got some weather coming in...
...so I'm suggesling that we tow you out
to the exchange point.
Butwsneedsomeonetocomeaboard
andnegofietelhedeal.
It's an ambush.
Captain.
Okay.
It's an ambush.
Keep me posted on slams.
- Roger.
- Comms test radio check.
OSS, TAO, I need eyes on the RHIB.
I need eyes on the RHIB.
Caplain's in Combat.
Taclical command
is now with the SEAL team.
TAO, where we at?
RHIBs are headed inbound
to the lifeboat.
HdybwbnamBoxaraieéalﬂmby
ioryouroldels.
ASTMLTAD,
hnedashlusatHdybwbdshab.
You need to be slrong.
Don't let anyone in.
Whatever happens, don't shop.
It's my job.
Evervlhing good, Irish.
Everylhing gonna be okay.
I go Navy ship...
...get dollars...
comm.
ltwassupposedtobeeasy.
I take ship...
...IlnSom...
...nobody get hurt.
You had $30,000
and a way to Somalia.
It wasn't enough?
Igol: bosses.
They got rules.
We all got bosses.
There's gull: be something
other thn being fishermn...
...and kidnapping people.
Maybe in America, Irish.
Maybe in America.
Alabama lifeboat, this is the U.S. Navy.
Open the halnh.
Gun down. Put the gun down.
Rel. I need to sea the plain.
- I show you plain. Back.
-Rel.
I show you plain. Back.
- Come on up.
- Back.
Listen.
- We gull: move our other boat clr.
-Up.
We gull: hook up tuwline.
- No hicks.
- No hicks. No hicks.
We just wanna see the caplain...
...and then get you to the ship
for the meeling with the elders.
Anvlhina happen, he die.
Anything happen, he die. I tell you.
- Sir, we have ears on the boat.
- Check.
Okay, here he comes.
Be advised,
I have eyes on the package.
Cammuevwvkﬂﬂ?
- Yeah, yeah. Are you taking care of this?
- This'll be over soon.
And, caplain, I got a uniform,
a clean uniform.
I need you to wear this.
And slay in the seat
you've been siﬂing in.
Put this on, caplain.
We need to keep you healthy.
It's very important
that ws keep you healthy-
Slay calm. It's going to be okay.
- Go back.
- Just relax.
Here, take it.
Inside. Go.
Go.
- Where are the elders?
- The elders are being ﬂown in.
Put lhe gun inside.
We'll lake you to your elders.
Anvlhina happen, he die.
I give you my word.
Everylhing will be fine.
Put the gun down.
Gun down.
Wait.
Come on aboard. Just relax.
- Take my hand.
- Relax.
We're almost there. Relax.
We got you. Come on.
Nice and easy. Okay.
Everylhing's gonna be okﬂY-
Caplain, it'll be over soon. Hang tough.
Slay in the same seat
you've been siﬂing in.
Two-two-four feet.
Stern seas.
Okay, the wind shouldn't be a factor.
Where do we need to be?
Shfis $235 Indus.
Sir, one Somali is exlraclaed.
RHIB is headed inbound.
Towline is aﬂached.
- TAO, let's iniliahe high-speed maneuver.
- Aye, sir.
Helyburton, Boxer. This is Beinbridge.
Commence high-speed maneuvers.
Over.
Bring him over here.
Here.
Okay, gel: il: oil' of him.
Come up this way. Up this way.
HW. go fight here.
I'm Chief O'Brien.
Let's get you taken care of inside.
Take him inside. Get him looked at.
- Can I see your hand?
- No. Where elders?
We'll ialk bout that leller.
We're going this way.
Through this door. Walnh your head.
This way. Let's go.
Stand over here.
One suspected pirate on board
in the slarboard hangar.
- Copy that.
- Hold it.
Right there.
Where are the elders?
The elders will be here soon.
Relax. We're gonna lake care of you.
Your oaplain knows what he's doing.
You're gonna get your money now.
What's going on?
I can't see.
Give me the radio.
Too much light. We no see.
We're going to iniliahe the tow.
Impact,
waelsqoingbirlifiebihebw.
You need to tell your driver
that he needs to slay in his
...and continue steering.
Alfa team is green at this time.
One green, two red.
Lifeboafs under tow.
We're at five knots.
Copy that.
We need three iargels green.
Keepkéeadyleepiiﬂﬂlﬂ.
- Hey. Hey.
-I'm just: pulling on the shirt like they id.
If he moves again, shoot him.
- Sir,1he pirates have just issued a threat.
- What's the hanslafion?
'If he moves again, shoot him.'
It's geﬂing rough.
Keepkdlaiqm.
TAD- We-
High-speed maneuvers are creafing big
waves headed inbound on the lifeboat.
Slow down! You make waves!
What kind of games are they playing?
I can't hold it slraight.
Be a man. Just shut up and sheer.
American ship, answer me.
U.S.A., answer me!
Alfa's green. Bravo and Charlie are red.
Too much waves!
U.S. Navy. Too much waves!
Alabama lifeboat, lhis is negulialor.
We'll pull you into our wake.
Ifyoulideinolnwdnifllbesrlndtner.
Negofiebrwt.
Irish. Irish. What you doing?
What you doing?
Alfa team green. One green, two red.
Give me a dislanoe.
Two twenty. Sfill 129 out.
Stop writing, Irish.
If he sees you, he kill me and you bolh.
American ship.
Answer me.
U.S. Navy, unwed!
I speak to Muse!
I want to speak with him!
Alfa and Charlie teams green.
Bravo red.
Alabama lifeboat, this is the neguliahor.
Your leader is in the helo hangar
wailing for the elders.
Where are the elders?
Where are elders?
American ship, answer!
L-lay-
Hey! What is this?
What is this you writing? Tell me!
They've got something going on.
I think it's a fight.
Stop! StoPI
Pull up the audio.
TAO, give me Screen 3 on the left.
Stop him.
Bilal, shop him.
Stop Irish! Stop Irish!
Bring the rope!
Alfa and Charlie are red.
We are three red.
Alabama lifeboat, this is the neguliahor.
If you harm the hoslage,
we do not have a deal.
DoyouwPY?
Tie him!
Alabama lifeboat, if you harm
the hoslage, we do not have a deal.
Do you understand?
What are you doing?
Caplain Phillips, can you hear me?
- Caplain Phillips, can you hear me?
- He's screaming, sir.
- One fifty-five. They're 64 meters out.
- One fifty-five, check. Speed up the tow.
Shut up!
Gd! a blindfold!
Can you see this?
Canyouseeit?
Let's reaoquire iargels,
weapons release on my command.
One thirty-five meters.
That's 44 out from oplimal.
Alfa green.
Bravo and Charlie are slill red. Two red.
Blindfold him.
Kid, just put your hands up.
You're just a kid.
Put your weapons down
and put your hands up.
Put your hands up!
Is anybody hearing this?
Tell my family I love lhem.
Andrea, I love you.
I love you, Ange.
Honey, I love you.
I love you. Danny. I'm 50W-
I'm sorry I'm here
and not there with you.
Can anybody hear this?
I can't stand this anymore.
One thirty meters.
That's 39 out from oplimal.
Two ted. No shit. Si“ than ted.
I need sights on iargels.
I need three iargels green.
Don't kill him!
The elders are coming.
We will get our money.
Youalebothiiuﬂs.
No one is coming.
Alfa green, Bravo green.
Two green, one red.
- One twenty-one. Thirty meters out.
- I can't take any more.
I'm all done.
That's it. We will all die if you kill him.
Evalyﬂ-ning they told you was lie!
They will kill us all...
...and he is behind everylhingl
- One seventeen meters.
- Two green, one red.
- We do not have a shot.
- I need eyes on.
Sir, they're gonna shoot him.
- Gun drawn. Gun drawn.
Stop the tow.
Roger. Stop the tow.
Execute.
What was that?
Oh, no!
We're gonna get you out of here
and get you home.
- Take him down. The hostage is safe.
- Get down.
- Put your head down.
- What?
- Good job, gum. We got them.
- Three Tangos down.
Mﬂainfiiﬂfipsisfieandenmm.
Well done, everybody.
- Right here. Go to this guy right here.
-Come with ma, plain.
You just sit down.
Neywokﬂﬂfilﬂfidan?
This way.
.Wgmh your slap.
Step.
Careful, sir.
Welcome aboard. These gum are gonna
take you to medical, get you checked out.
HM 1, he has impact injuries.
He's in shock.
Okay. Are you able to walk okay, sil?
Are you okay? What's your name?
Rich. Rich Phillips.
We're gonna turn you over
to the Department of Juslioe.
You're going to America to face trial.
You shoot my friends?
Caplain Phillips is free.
All of your friends are dead.
It's over. You're going to America now.
You have been suspected of piracy.
I am now gonna read you your rights.
You have the right to remain silent
and make no slatement.
Any siatament can be used against you
in judicial proceedings.
Caplain Phillips, please come in.
Haveaseat.
Trauma shears.
I'm Chief O'Brien.
I'll be your oorpsman today.
Can you please tell me
what's going on?
Can you talk?
- Can you tell me what's going on?
- Yeah.
I'm okﬂY-
Are you okay?
Because you don't look okay.
Ara you in ny pain right noun'?
Are you in pain right now?
Right there, on your side.
Okay. Let me see it really quick.
Can you lift up your arm?
Does that hurt?
- Li'lﬂe bit?
- Li'lﬂe bit.
Is it tendel?
Go ahead and put your arm down.
I need you to look at me. Calm down...
...and I need you to breathe.
Deep breaths.
There you go- Very 900d-
Awesome.
Now I want you to relax your arm.
We're gonna put this on,
get your heart rate and oxygen level...
-...make sure you're breathing.
- Okay.
- I want you to keep doing that, okay?
- Gonna put this on your finger.
Can you tell me what happened
to your head?
Put it on your finger.
ThGY-ﬂ-
It's okay, take your time.
There's a 2-oenlimeler laoerafion
on the left eyebrow.
It's okay. It's all right.
- Okay. Okay.
- I want you to look at me and breathe.
Understand?
- Yeah.
Okay. all right.
Hfisqdaboufinnlu gap.
Uﬂshnelalionfinteonfinmtemph.
- Got it.
- Okay. Very good.
All right. You're doing great, okay?
Did all this blood come
from your eyebrow and your head?
Whit?
Did the blood come
from your eyebrow and your head?
- All of this.
- Well, no, not all of it.
- Okay.
- That's not mine.
Okay, all right, all right. Look at me.
- We're gonna lay you down.
- Okay.
- All fight.
- Yeah.
I want you to lay down nice and genﬂy.
Nice and genﬂy.
You're okay. I 911i W"-
There you go- Very 900d-
Caplain, you're safe now, okay?
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- You're okay.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
- Does my family know?
- Your family lawws you're safe.
You'll be able to call lhem
as soon as you are taken care of.
Sir, I need you to breathe, okay?
You are safe and you are fine.
It's gonna be okay.
Everylhing's gonna be okﬂY-